RG 166:005, Connecticut 375 Commission
Connecticut State Library
Connecticut 375 Commission records
1961-2010
2010
Connecticut State Library
Connecticut 375 Commission
3 cubic feet
The 375 Commission was established by Executive Order 37 signed by Governor M. Jodi Rell on January 20, 2010. The Commission raised funds and developed events and festivities during the year long anniversary.
RG166_005
2011-074
Biographical Note
On January 20, 2010, Governor M. Jodi Rell signed Executive Order 37, which recognized 2010 as a year of celebration and thanksgiving for our founders and their successors who made Connecticut a great and prosperous state. The order also established a "375 Commission" that developed recommendations for events, festivities, fundraising and commemorative memorabilia. The Commission was made up of historians, educators, arts, culture representatives, and fund-raisers.
The 375 Kickoff Celebration was held on February 17, 2010 with Governor Rell leading a procession of school children, Boy Scouts, Girl Scouts, lawmakers and municipal officials from the State Capitol to the State Library. Numerous activities occurred throughout the state. The largest portion of the collection documents the Youth Art Contest, sponsored by the 375 Commission.
Scope and Content
The records are arranged into four series: Administrative Files, Activities and Events, Removable Media, and Artifacts.
Series 1. Administrative Files, 1961-2010, includes a draft copy of Executive Order 37; a form fundraising letter and a mailing list of individuals; agendas; minutes; attachments and unsigned handwritten notes; lists of Commission members; information about collaboration with Connecticut Public Television (CPTV); publications; stickers; development of the 375th Anniversary website; background research conducted to plan the anniversary; a research report on the Tercentenary Celebration and the 350th Anniversary; and miscellaneous research notes.
Series 2. Activities and Events, 2010, documents the various activities and events sponsored by the 375 commission. The events include a 375 Kickoff Celebration, Connecticut Open House Day, Free State Park Day and a Youth Art Contest. Other activities included participation in 4-H Citizenship Day, the EASTCONN interdistrict service learning project and the receipt of a painting of the Charter Oak by Mark Patnode. Also includes draft calendars of events.
Series 3. Removable Media, 2010, includes 8 compact discs documenting various activities held during the 375 anniversary including the Kickoff Celebration, the Youth Art Contest, and Free Parks Day. There are 2 compact discs which document the work of Nora Duncan, Policy and Legislative Affairs Liaison; one with emails and one with documents in various formats. This series also includes a CD of songs about Connecticut, submitted by Dave Downs to the Commission.
Series 4. Artifacts, 2010, include two commemorative items, a mug and two sets of coasters depicting the image of the Charter Oak created by artist Mark Patnode.
Arrangement
Arranged in four series:
Series 1. Administrative Files, 1961-2010, is further arranged into the following subseries: Press Files and Research. Each file is arranged chronologically with undated material at the end of the folder.
Series 2. Activities and Events, 2010, is arranged alphabetically by the name of the event. Within the subseries of Youth Art Contest, the folders are arranged alphabetically by the name of the town and then alphabetically by the name of the school, if there is more than one school represented in a town. Oversized artwork has been removed to box 3. The 8 finalist panels have been removed to oversize map case drawer 92.
Series 3. Removable Media, 2010, has been removed from various files and placed in box 4.
Series 4. Artifacts, 2010, has been removed to box 5.
Related Material
None.
Index Terms
Organizations:
Connecticut 375 Commission
Persons:
Patnode, Mark; Duncan, Nora
Subjects:
Art -- Competitions; Child artists; Connecticut -- History; Connecticut -- Anniversaries, etc.; Connecticut -- Social life and customs; Connecticut Public Television
Document Types:
Agendas; Calendars; Compact discs; Clippings; Competition drawings; Correspondence; Coasters (containers); DVDs; Membership lists; Minutes; Mugs; Press releases; Reports; Watercolors (paintings)
Restrictions on Access
Series 3. Removable Media, 2010, is restricted. Contact State Archives staff for assistance.
These records are stored at an off-site facility and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.
See the policy.
Provenance
The records were transferred to the Connecticut State Library from the Office of the Governor on December 14, 2010.
Container List
- Series 1. Administrative Files, 1961-2010
  - Executive Order, 2010 January (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Fundraising, 2010 March (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Meeting agendas and minutes, 2010 January-March (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Membership lists, 2010 March, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous, 2010 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Press Files
    - Connecticut Public Television (CPTV), 2010 March, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Publications, 2010 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Stickers, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Website development, 2010 January, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Research
    - Miscellaneous, 2010 February, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Planning, 2010 January-March, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Reports, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Series 2. Activities and Events, 2010
  - 375 Kickoff, 2010 February, undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 4-H Citizenship Day, undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Big E, 2010 June-July (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Calendar of events, 2010 July (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Connecticut Open House Day, 2010 March (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - EastCONN, 2010 June (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Free Parks Day & Letterboxing, 2010 March-May (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Painting, Charter Oak, by Mark Patnode, 2010 March-May (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Youth Art Contest, 2010
    - Administrative Files
      - Finalists, 2010 (Box 1, Folder 21)
      - Finalists in the 375 Commission Youth Art Contest, 2010; 8 panels (Box 92)
      - Miscellaneous, 2010 (Box 1, Folder 22)
      - Press files, 2010 (Box 1, Folder 23)
      - Runners up, 2010 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Entries by School or Organization
      - Avon-Roaring Brook Elementary School, entries and entry forms, 2010 (Box 1, Folder 25-26)
      - Bethel-St. Mary School, entries and entry forms, 2010 (Box 1, Folder 27-28)
      - Bloomfield-Laurel School, entry, 2010 (Box 3, Folder 1)
      - Bloomfield-Laurel School, entry form, 2010 (Box 1, Folder 29)
      - Danbury-St. Gregory the Great School, entries and entry forms, 2010 (Box 1, Folder 30-31)
      - Danbury-St. Joseph School, entries, 2010 (Box 1, Folder 32)
      - Ellington-Crystal Lake School, entry and entry form, 2010 (Box 1, Folder 33)
      - Hartford-Boys & Girls Club of Hartford, entries and entry forms, 2010 (Box 1, Folder 34-35)
      - Hartford-Jumoke Academy, entries and entry forms, 2010 (Box 1, Folder 36-37)
      - Hartford-Parkville Elementary, entries and entry forms, 2010 (Box 1, Folder 38-39)
      - Hartford-Rawson School, entries, 2010 (Box 3, Folder 2)
      - Hartford-Rawson School, entry forms, 2010 (Box 1, Folder 40)
      - Mansfield-Mansfield Middle School, entry and entry form, 2010 (Box 2, Folder 1)
      - Meriden-Israel Putnam School, entry and entry form, 2010 (Box 2, Folder 2)
      - Middlefield-The Independent Day School, entries and entry forms, 2010 (Box 2, Folder 3-4)
      - Middlefield-John Lyman School, entries, 2010 (Box 2, Folder 5)
      - Moodus-Nathan Hale-Ray Middle School, entries and entry forms, 2010 (Box 2, Folder 6-7)
      - Mystic-Northeast Academy, entry and entry form, 2010 (Box 2, Folder 8)
      - Norwalk-Girl Scout Troop #464, entries and entry forms, 2010 (Box 2, Folder 9-10)
      - Norwalk-Side by Side School, entry and entry form, 2010 (Box 2, Folder 11)
      - Norwalk-Rowayton School, entries and entry forms, 2010 (Box 2, Folder 12-13)
      - Orange-Race Brook School, entries and entry forms, 2010 (Box 2, Folder 14-15)
      - Pawcatuck-St. Michael School, entry and entry form, 2010 (Box 2, Folder 16)
      - Putnam-St. Mary School, entries and entry forms, 2010 (Box 2, Folder 17-18)
      - Southington-Hatton Elementary School, entry and entry form, 2010 (Box 2, Folder 19)
      - Stamford-Holy Spirit School, entries and entry forms, 2010 (Box 2, Folder 20-21)
      - Trumbull-St. Catherine of Siena, entry and entry form, 2010 (Box 2, Folder 22)
      - Unknown school, entry, 2010 (Box 3, Folder 3)
      - Unknown school, entries, 2010 (Box 2, Folder 23)
      - Waterbury-B.W. Tinker School, entry and entry form, 2010 (Box 2, Folder 24)
      - Waterbury-Carrington School, entry, 2010 (Box 3, Folder 4)
      - Waterbury-Carrington School, entry form, 2010 (Box 2, Folder 25)
      - Waterbury-Rotella Interdistrict Magnet School, entries and entry forms, 2010 (Box 2, Folder 26-27)
      - Waterbury-St. Frances Xavier School, entry and entry form, 2010 (Box 2, Folder 28)
      - Waterbury-Wendell Cross School, entry, 2010 (Box 3, Folder 5)
      - Waterbury-Wendell Cross School, entry form, 2010 (Box 2, Folder 29)
      - West Hartford-Norfeldt Elementary School, entries and entry forms, 2010 (Box 2, Folder 30-31)
      - West Simsbury-Tootin' Hills School, entry and entry form, 2010 (Box 2, Folder 32)
      - Wethersfield-Highcrest Elementary School, entries and entry forms, 2010 (Box 2, Folder 33-34)
      - Windsor-Trinity Christian School, entries and entry forms, 2010 (Box 2, Folder 35-36)
      - Woodbridge-Ezra Academy, entries and entry forms, 2010 (Box 2, Folder 37-38)
- Series 3. Removable Media, 2010
  RESTRICTED
  - 375 emails - Duncan, 2010; 1 compact disc, 238 MB (Box 4, Folder 1)
    1 Microsoft Office Outlook PST file.
    This item is separated from the records. Contact State Archives staff for assistance.
  - 375 kickoff, 2010 February 17; 1 compact disc, 452 MB (Box 4, Folder 2)
    90 jpegs of the 375 kickoff event from the State Capitol to the State Library.
  - 375 kickoff, 2010 February 17; 1 compact disc, 24.9 MB (Box 4, Folder 3)
    23 jpegs of the 375 kickoff, statues in State Capitol Building, and south view looking toward the State Library
  - 375 scrapbook, 2010; 1 compact disc, 16.1 MB (Box 4, Folder 4)
    27 jpegs of various 375 events and speakers.
  - Booth Hill School 6th Grade Play, PM Class, 2010 June; 1 DVD, 3.69 GB, 40 min., 30 sec. (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Connecticut music by Dave Downs, 2010; 1 compact disc, 12 tracks, 42 min., 06 sec. (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Free Parks event at Heublein, 2010 May 14; 1 compact disc, 702 MB (Box 4, Folder 7)
    80 jpegs of event at Heublein Tower, Talcott Mountain State Park.
  - Youth Art Contest 15 finalist images, 2010; 1 compact disc, 9.15 MB (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Series 4. Artifacts, 2010
  - Artifacts, 2010 (Box 5)